#### SHIVAM AGNIHOTRI

Mobile: +91 7066145884 / 8788090882 | Email: <a href="mailto:agnihotrishivam@rocketmail.com">agnihotrishivam@rocketmail.com</a> | Passport Number: R4471989 | Skype Id: live:shivamagnihotri82 | LinkedIn URL: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/shivam-agnihotri-31a3ba107/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/shivam-agnihotri-31a3ba107/</a>

### **SUMMARY**

Having 5+ years of experience on various skills like AWS (EC2, S3, VPC, Route53, IAM, Security groups, ELB, ACM, RDS), Python (boto3), Docker/ECS Kubernetes/EKS. Having experience on CI/CD pipelines for code deployment using Git, Code Pipeline, Terraform. Having experience on Linux administration, onboarding project on AWS, Trusted advisor.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Company	Designation	Duration
Birla soft	Sr. Consultant	Jan 2020 - Till Date
T- Systems	Consultant	Feb 2018 - Sep 2019
Blazeclan technologies	Cloud Engineer	Sep 2016 - Feb 2018

Lafarge Holcim: (42 Clients) Roles and Responsibility:

• Design of AWS infrastructure deploying the infrastructure with application. Establishing the CICD and automate the infrastructure by using Devops tools and different AWS services.

**Technology:** AWS, Python, Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, GIT, Prometheus and Grafana dashboards.

Virago: (25 Clients) Roles and Responsibility:

• Configuring, Migration and deployment of various AWS resources as per client demand. Deployment and design in T mobiles products on cloud infrastructure.

Technology: AWS, Linux, Lambda, Codepipeline, Codecommit, Codedeploy, Elastic Beanstalk, Platespin tool.

2nd Watch: (30 Clients) Roles and Responsibility:

• Handling all operational and service requests for all cloud based applications. Automation of monitoring and day all day to day task. Migrating On premises infrastructure to AWS.

**Technology:** AWS, Python, Linux, GIT, Terraform, Cloudformation.

# **KEY SKILLS**

- Setting up the basic AWS services like EC2, VPC, S3, Route53, RDS, DynamoDB as per the client's requirements.
- Continuously monitoring and supporting the existing AWS infrastructure by using cloudwatch and NagiOS.
- Implementation and Management the VPN for client's secured access to their infrastructure. (Openvpn)
- Implementation and support of AWS cloud based infrastructure and its solutions.
- Creation and implementation of code as infrastructure by using CFT and Terraform.
- Setting up the monitoring solutions by using cloud watch and service now.
- Implementation and support of CICD solutions using AWS services like Code-pipeline, Code-deploy, Code-commit etc.
- Integrate the Devops tools like GIT and Ansible with Jenkins to set up CICD application deployment.
- Implementation and support of CICD solutions using Jenkins and build tools like maven and ansible.
- Automate remediate the daily scheduled activities by using python boto3 and AWS lambda service.
- Setting up all the AWS best practices in clients AWS account for security purpose.
- Detect and Auto-remediate the security solutions by using AWS control tower and AWS lambda.
- Managing and maintaining all the source code for application deployment and infrastructure code by using GIT.
- Resolving all the merge conflicts for GIT version control systems.
- Managing and supporting the Containerization by using ECS and docker.
- Proficient with container systems like Docker and container orchestration like EC2 Container Service, Kubernetes, worked with Terraform.

- Experience with container-based deployments using Docker, working with Docker images, Docker Hub and Docker-registries and Kubernetes.
- Orchestration and implementation of kubernetes and EKS service as per clients requirements.
- Log rotation, User management, troubleshooting web applications, setting up cron jobs in Linux platform.
- Design and implement shell script to automate all Linux tasks.
- Setting up the ADFS active directory federation service to engage multiple AWS accounts from single resource.

## **TECHNICAL PROFICIENCY**

Cloud:	AWS, Azure, Openstack
OS:	Linux (Amazon linux, RHEL, SUSE, Ubuntu, Windows)
SCM:	GIT, Codecommit
Security	AWS WAR, Cloud Confirmity
CI	Jenkins, AWS Code Build.
CD	AWS Code Deploy, Jenkins.
Containers	Docker, AWS ECS, AWS Fargate.
Serverless	AWS Lambda
Scripting	Python, Shell, JSON, YAML.
IAAC	Terraform, Cloud Formation.
Language	Python 3.7

### **EDUCATION**

• B.E. from Marathwada Institute of Technology, Aurangabad (Dr. Babasaheb Ambedkar Marathwada University). 2016

## **KEY ACHIEVEMENTS**

- AWS Certified Solution Architect Professional Level.
- AWS Certified Solution Architect Associate Level.
- Redhat Certified Engineer (RHEL7.0)

References will be provided upon request